<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-27T10:51:15+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">PYDV</title><subtitle>Thought repository</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Vacation in Kashmir</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/kashmir/2024/12/25/Kashmir.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vacation in Kashmir" /><published>2024-12-25T00:12:01+05:30</published><updated>2024-12-25T00:12:01+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/india/kashmir/2024/12/25/Kashmir</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/kashmir/2024/12/25/Kashmir.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-0---wednesday-25th-december-2024">Day 0 - Wednesday, 25th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="arrival-in-srinagar-kashmir">Arrival in Srinagar, Kashmir</h2>

<p>Arrived in Kashmir via a direct Indigo flight from Hyderabad. Took about 2 hours 45 minutes.
Airport pickup by arranged Innova cab that would be with us throughout the tour.
Checkin at accomodation. Too late for Christmas celebration. Cold, but no snow.</p>

<h1 id="day-1---thursday-26th-december-2024">Day 1 - Thursday, 26th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="gondola-ride-in-gulmarg">Gondola ride in Gulmarg</h2>

<h1 id="day-2---friday-27th-december-2024">Day 2 - Friday, 27th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="tangmarg-and-return-to-srinagar">Tangmarg and return to Srinagar</h2>

<h1 id="day-3---saturday-28th-december-2024">Day 3 - Saturday, 28th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="hazrat-bal-mughal-darban-chai-jaai-lal-chowk">Hazrat Bal, Mughal Darban, Chai Jaai, Lal Chowk</h2>

<h1 id="day-4---sunday-29th-december-2024">Day 4 - Sunday, 29th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="shikara-ride-in-dal-lake-nishat-garden-chashme-shahi">Shikara ride in Dal lake, Nishat Garden, Chashme Shahi</h2>

<h1 id="day-5---monday-30th-december-2024">Day 5 - Monday, 30th December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="travel-to-pahalgam">Travel to Pahalgam</h2>

<h1 id="day-6---tuesday-31st-december-2024">Day 6 - Tuesday, 31st December 2024</h1>
<h2 id="pahalgam-new-years-eve">Pahalgam, New Year’s Eve</h2>

<h1 id="day-7---wednesday-1st-january-2025">Day 7 - Wednesday, 1st January 2025</h1>
<h2 id="anchbal-garden-verinag">Anchbal garden, Verinag</h2>

<h1 id="day-8---thursday-2nd-january-2025">Day 8 - Thursday, 2nd January 2025</h1>
<h2 id="shopping-at-shahjee-shameyana-lunch-departure-from-srinagar">Shopping at Shahjee, Shameyana Lunch, departure from Srinagar</h2>

<p>Cab Expenses: 3k * 8 days + 2k for airport pickup + 2k for Verinag trip = 28k + 1.5k tip</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="india" /><category term="kashmir" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 0 - Wednesday, 25th December 2024 Arrival in Srinagar, Kashmir]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">South Goa trip</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/goa/2024/08/19/Goa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="South Goa trip" /><published>2024-08-19T00:12:01+05:30</published><updated>2024-08-19T00:12:01+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/india/goa/2024/08/19/Goa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/goa/2024/08/19/Goa.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-0---wednesday-14th-august-2024">Day 0 - Wednesday, 14th August 2024</h1>
<h2 id="departure-from-pune">Departure from Pune</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Ashray Amrutyog private bus from Swargate (approx. 2500 per person)</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="day-1---thursday-15th-august-2024">Day 1 - Thursday, 15th August 2024</h1>
<h2 id="arrival-in-madgaon-cafe-zilo-galgibaga-beach">Arrival in Madgaon, Cafe Zilo, Galgibaga beach</h2>
<p>Rented Activa 5g scooty from Santosh Rentals just outside the Madgaon Bus-Stand. (INR 700 * 4 days) 2800 cost + 1000 cash deposit.
Coffee at Cafe Zilo. Travelled to Canacona via Varca-&gt;Covallasim-&gt;Betul-&gt;Agonda (approx 2 hrs). Checked in at Pont Bleu Suites neat Sandolxem Bridge. One pool, Lush green property. 3 suites river facing + 1 upper suite facing the pool. 
Our room, pool facing, was half glass. No kitchen in property. Also had a villa 1km down the road.
Ordered Lunch from Highway Restaurant (Chinese). Galgibaga beach in the evening 5km away. Cloudy. Ordered Dinner from Aditya Restaurant near Canacona station.</p>

<h1 id="day-2---friday-16th-august-2024">Day 2 - Friday, 16th August 2024</h1>
<h2 id="taplona-beach-the-mills-pallolem-beach-cafe-feta">Taplona beach, The Mills, Pallolem Beach, Cafe Feta</h2>
<p>Morning chill at Taplona. Lunch at Deepshika Restaurant on the beach. Thali. Fish. Breezers.
Noon rest at Resort. Snack at The Mills. Evening at Pallolem Beach. Crowded. Bought fibre bag for 650. Dinner at Cafe Feta (Pizza and lemon soda). Blueberry cheese cake good.</p>

<h1 id="day-3---saturday-17th-august-2024">Day 3 - Saturday, 17th August 2024</h1>
<h2 id="taplona-beach-butterfly-beach-cafe-zali">Taplona beach, Butterfly Beach, Cafe Zali</h2>
<p>Morning chill at Taplona. Lunch at Deepshika Restaurant on the beach. Thali. Fish. Breezers.
Noon rest at Resort. Late noon leave for butterly beach hike. Super crowded. Slushy path. 100 entry fee. Bad to worse roads. Worst beach due to crowd.
Eveing snack at Cafe Zali. Good views. Expensive. Dinner at Feta again (White Pasta). Tiramisu yum.</p>

<h1 id="day-4---sunday-18th-august-2024">Day 4 - Sunday, 18th August 2024</h1>
<h2 id="taplona-beach-cape-goa-cabo-de-rama-cafe-carvela">Taplona beach, Cape Goa (Cabo de Rama), Cafe Carvela</h2>
<p>Morning stroll at Taplona. Checkout by 11:30. Travel 1hr 30m to Cape Goa for Lunch. Great food (Veg Burger and Mushroom/CaramelizedOnion/Cheese sandwich) and great ambience.
Souveniers and Kaju on the way. Extra 100 petrol just for emergency. Cafe Caravelo.
Kill Time in Pantaloons nearby. Bus departs from Madgaon Bus Stand at 19:30 (Ashray Elite).</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="india" /><category term="goa" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 0 - Wednesday, 14th August 2024 Departure from Pune]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - Amsterdam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/30/Amsterdam.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - Amsterdam" /><published>2024-05-30T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-30T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/30/Amsterdam</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/30/Amsterdam.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-13---friday-30th-may-2024">Day 13 - Friday, 30th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="arrival-in-amsterdam-canal-cruise">Arrival in Amsterdam, Canal Cruise</h2>

<h1 id="day-14---saturday-31st-may-2024">Day 14 - Saturday, 31st May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="amsterdam---zaansche-saans">Amsterdam - Zaansche Saans</h2>

<h1 id="day-15---sunday-1st-june-2024">Day 15 - Sunday, 1st June 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="amsterdam---harlem-red-light-district">Amsterdam - Harlem, Red light district</h2>

<h1 id="day-16---monday-2nd-june-2024">Day 16 - Monday, 2nd June 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="amsterdam---vondelpark-departure-from-schiphol-airport">Amsterdam - Vondelpark, departure from Schiphol Airport</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 13 - Friday, 30th May 2024. Arrival in Amsterdam, Canal Cruise]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - Berlin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/27/Berlin.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - Berlin" /><published>2024-05-27T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-27T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/27/Berlin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/27/Berlin.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-10---thursday-27th-may-2024">Day 10 - Thursday, 27th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="berlin---east-side-gallery-alexanderplatz">Berlin - East Side Gallery, Alexanderplatz</h2>

<h1 id="day-11---thursday-28th-may-2024">Day 11 - Thursday, 28th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="berlin---bundestag-branderburg-tor-holocost-memorial-topography-of-terror-hitlers-bunker-charlie-checkpoint">Berlin - Bundestag, Branderburg Tor, Holocost Memorial, Topography of Terror, Hitler’s Bunker, Charlie Checkpoint</h2>

<h1 id="day-12---thursday-29th-may-2024">Day 12 - Thursday, 29th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="berlin---under-der-linden-humbolt-forum-museum-island-alexanderplatz">Berlin - Under der Linden, Humbolt forum, Museum Island, Alexanderplatz</h2>

<h1 id="day-13---friday-30th-may-2024">Day 13 - Friday, 30th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="departure-from-berlin">Departure from Berlin</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 10 - Thursday, 27th May 2024. Berlin - East Side Gallery, Alexanderplatz]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - Munich</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/23/Munich.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - Munich" /><published>2024-05-23T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-23T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/23/Munich</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/23/Munich.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-6---thursday-23th-may-2024">Day 6 - Thursday, 23th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="munich---altstadt">Munich - Altstadt</h2>

<p>The train, Deutch Bahn (DB), from Stuttgart to Munich was from 11:00-13:00 approx. We were still early for our checkin at Euro Youth Hostel, right outside the station (always called Hauptbahn hof - Hbf), which was 14:00. We waited in the lounge near the bar, reading up tourism pamphlets. The hostel gave us a discount of 10%, in cash!, for taking a double bed in the 10bed dorm since we were a couple. Neat pocket money! Also complemntary beer at the bar. The room was crammed and home for 4 nights but we didnt mind since we would mostly be out and about exploring Munich and nearby places.</p>

<p>Later that day we went exploring the old town (Alt-Stadt). Seeing Rathausen etc. and the market place. Felaffel for dinner, first of many fealafels i was to have in Germany. Such is the vegetarian life. The scars in my gums from eating Tomato-mozarella sandwich had almost begun to heal. There was also a cool Thai outlet near our hostel. we twice ended up packing food to eat in hostel bar lounge.</p>

<p>Night we spent researching Neuschwanstein Castle for which we had booked tickets for Friday evening 17:10.
Room was stuffy so i cracked open the back door at night and no one seemed to mind.
The bathrooms were downstairs outside so that was a big hassle though. Anyway, sleep comes easy when you walk 20000+ steps a day for a week.</p>

<h1 id="day-7---friday-24th-may-2024">Day 7 - Friday, 24th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="day-trip-to-neuschwanstein-castle">Day trip to Neuschwanstein Castle</h2>

<h1 id="day-8---saturday-25th-may-2024">Day 8 - Saturday, 25th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="day-trip-to-innsbruck">Day trip to Innsbruck</h2>

<h1 id="day-9---sunday-26th-may-2024">Day 9 - Sunday, 26th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="munich---bmw-welt-rathaus-english-garten-fuhrer-bau-aldstat-beer-garten">Munich - BMW Welt, Rathaus, English Garten, Fuhrer Bau, Aldstat, Beer Garten</h2>

<h1 id="day-10---monday-27th-may-2024">Day 10 - Monday, 27th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="departure-from-munich">Departure from Munich</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 6 - Thursday, 23th May 2024. Munich - Altstadt]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - Stuttgart</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/21/Stuttgart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - Stuttgart" /><published>2024-05-21T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-21T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/21/Stuttgart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/21/Stuttgart.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="day-4---tuesday-21st-may-2024">Day 4 - Tuesday, 21st May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="stuttgart">Stuttgart</h2>

<p>We arrived in Stuttgart at almost 19:00 from Paris (Gar de’Est) where we were received by my wife’s friend with flowers, cake and chocolates for our first anniversary!
We reached our hotel (Ibis Budget) by metro (U-bahn). After circling the block in search of a restaurant, for it was almost 21:00, we had dinner at a good Italian restaurant nearby (ARIA, Restaurante Enoteca).
The Porche Design Centre was just 100m from our hotel! There were even some vine gardens.</p>

<p>The Ibis Budget was perhaps the cheapest accomodation in our Europe trip, a bit north of the main city centre, but quite comfortable. Room had a very heavy door, and it was our first encounter with unintutive Wuropean windows, which crack upwards and inwards. we had a cross ways bed above our twin bed accessible via a ladder. We kept banging our heads many times on the ramp. The toilet has no water supply, just toilet paper and a flush pot. the Bath was a seaprate space module type contraption. The tap was in the room itself which doubled as a dressing table of sorts. TV was near the window and attached to a sort of working desk. Area was really quiet. Beds were crisp and comfortable. It was often drizzling at times outside. Cars went super fast on the roads i noticed.</p>

<h1 id="day-5---wednesday-22nd-may-2024">Day 5 - Wednesday, 22nd May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="stuttgart-ferhnsturm-esslingen-stadtbibliotek">Stuttgart Ferhnsturm, Esslingen, Stadtbibliotek</h2>

<p>We started our day with some cheesecake that wife’s friend had got us yesterday. We bought a day trip ticket from the nearest U-bahn station. Not used to lack of people at public places like the metro, Germany was a surprisingly good experience of lot of personal space. We stopped at Stadtbibliotek to checkout the super clean and well maintained, spotlessly white, state library. It was a tourist site in itself! We then started for the nearby town of Esslingen with the friend as our guide.</p>

<p>Esslingen had that small town charm and was a clam break from our city touring. We saw the old church, vineyards, casually strolling, coffee here cake there. We had a big brunch at 1582 restaurant, yep, founded in 1582! Food was delicious and never in Europe had we had such a big meal until then. The potatoe salad and Ratatouie was heavenly. We also ordered sparkling water for 8 Euros because why not!</p>

<p>It was drizzling when we started back from the pictureqsue town. We took the bus to a Ubahn station then stopped at the Stuttgart TV tower (Ferhnsturm). 11 euros ticket each, courtesy the friend, and we were up! A 360 degree view of the beautiful city. It was raining when we started back to the hotel, saying goodbye to our friend.</p>

<p>We were stuffed from the lunch so no dinner, and we slept early.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 4 - Tuesday, 21st May 2024. Stuttgart]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - Paris</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/17/Paris.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - Paris" /><published>2024-05-17T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-17T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/17/Paris</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/17/Paris.html"><![CDATA[<p>For our first wedding anniversary we were determined to visit Paris, among other destinations in me and my wife’s first visit to Europe.</p>

<h1 id="departure-from-bom">Departure from BOM</h1>

<p>We took an outstation Ola sedan taxi from Pune, approx 16:00 on 16th May. The driver had an urge to fuel up on CNG just when the weather was turning bad. That meant we were on the expressway only by 17:00. We were caught in intense downpour on the eway, with more intimidating cars splashing our car causing whiteout at 80-90 kmph. Nevertheless, worse was yet to come.</p>

<p>Just when we thought we are almost at the airport (&lt;4km), we found ourselves reluctant participants in the infamous Saki Naka traffic jam, for full 2 hours. Just when I had finished contemplating my plan to walk to the airport (BOM T-2), the traffic loosened enough to allow us to reach the airport. We had accounted for such uncertainities so we still had enough time to checkin, emmigration etc.</p>

<p>Air France 217 was Boeing 777-200 (twin-jet, B772). The digital entertainment worked well, snacks tasty and blankets comfy. Arrived at CDG (Charles De Gaulle International Airport) Termial 2E at around 08:00 on Friday 17th May (CEST). Central Europe time was 03:30 mins behind India (IST). My Casio watch didn’t account for Daylight saving time so I had to set its time zone to Cairo for it to show actual time.</p>

<p>The Immigration line for non-EU/US etc. passports was crazy long and slow. Took about 1hr+ to reach the kiosk. Flights from Africa had just landed as well so the queue was extra long.</p>

<p>Luggage at our belt (which took some time to find) was loaded with other flight baggage as well, so our had been unloaded at the side which we didnt see for another 20mins. So 120mins after landing we were finally ready to go to the city!
We walked to the RER station, 10mins walk. Long queue to get tickets from kiosk, another 15 mins. Took 2 tickets to Paris, paid using Forex card. You just need to insert card and press okay, no PIN!! scary indeed.
RER train just starts at the CDG station so there wasnt any rush and we got a train soon (11:00).</p>

<h1 id="day-0---friday-17th-may-2024">Day 0 - Friday, 17th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="tour-de-eiffel-seine-river-cruise-montparnasse">Tour de Eiffel, Seine river cruise, Montparnasse</h2>

<p>We took the RER took us straight to Denfert Rocherau, and Line 6 Metro to Montparnasse Bienvenue. Hotel Terminus Montparnasse is right at one of the exits near Rue de Rennes. Having arrived 2 hours earlier, the staff was gracious to keep our baggage while we went about exploring the Montparnasse neighbourhood. Restaurant Bullion is right next door and specialises in French cuisine. It always had a queue of 10-30 people every time we were arriving at or leaving our hotel. There are quite a few restaurants around this neighbourhood. We adopted the Paris Boulongerie as our go to breakast place. Tomotoe and Mazarella sandwich being my stable while my wife enjoyed a partially larger range as she was non vegetarian. Leaving out beef and steak etc, it left only fish and chicken for her nourishment.</p>

<p>Tour de Montparnasse is unavoidable with its looming presence over the neighbourhood. It also provides excellent orientation, being just 2-300m from our hotel we always knew where our hotel was.</p>

<p>The hotel room was small but sufficient as we didn’t plan to stay indoors much given the long daylight hours, from almost 5am to 9pm. The batchroom was very small, but functional and needed a bit of effort to keep clean and dry. The Television only had one english channel, DW. No air-conditioning as we did not feel that the season required one.</p>

<p>As typical of any tourist visiting Paris for the first time, we rushed to Tour de Eiffel, taking the metro to Bir Hakim station. We also had prebooked a Seine river cruise with Beateaux Parisiens which leaves from right behind Eiffel near Pont de Lena bridge. Surprisingly the crowd was thin so, after standing in queue for 8-10mins, we got onspot tickets to walk up to 2nd Floor (11 Euro fper person). The walk is a bit of an exersize, specially to one’s things. The view was spectacular, of course. We located the Sacre Couer, Hotel Invalides, Pantheon, and of course, Tour Montparnasse. Lots of photographs and we walked down. We sat at the gardens along Jardin de Mars. Looked like Olympic venues were being readied on the three sides of the Eiffel for the oncoming Olympics 2024. There was even a timer near Pont de Lena. Boarding the evening cruise was a breeze, just scan the QR code and you are in. crowd was spare and most were seated on top as weather was good too. Not much announcements on what all we saw, but I did look it all up on Google maps. We first went towards Louvre and almost Pont Neuf. Then took a turn to go to pas Eiffel again towards Statue of Liberty and back to Pont de Lena. Almost 2 hours. We walked beside Eiffel, s street famous with instagrammers for the evening lights. The sparkling lights go off every hour after dark from 0 to 5th minute. We saw from 10:00-10:05. We then took a bus (Route 800) from Pont Neuf back to Montparnasse. It was late, around 11pm and only Mc Donalds was open. Not many vegetarian options here so i settled for cheese burger. It was meh, not good. Back to hotel after first day of almost 25000 step count!</p>

<h1 id="day-1---saturday-18th-may-2024">Day 1 - Saturday, 18th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="louvre-museum-latin-quarter-and-luxembourg-garden">Louvre Museum, Latin Quarter and Luxembourg Garden</h2>

<p>We had prebooked 10:00 am tickets to the Louvre for Saturday, 18th May. We woke up and had sandwich and coffee from the Boulongerie and headed to Louvre by Bus. The Bus dropped us right in front of the Glass Pyramid of Louvre. The queue to get inside was long but quick moving. We took lots of photos and then got in 10:00 am queue. Starting with the Denon wing with antiquities and the Mona Lisa. We saw Roman and greek statues and Egyptian antiquities. After a multitide of Italian and French paintings, we finally saw the Mona Lisa! The crowd was a spectacle as well. After almost 3 hours in the museum, we were out of water and forgot to refill botels at the museum, so when we exited from Carousel side, we immidiately bought 2 bottles from a South Asian vendor who was selling 500ml bottles for 1 euro each.</p>

<p>We then went to Jardin de Tuliers and lazed around while a Cheerleading practise was going on.
We ate packaged snacks and started walking towards Ile de la Cite and the Latin quarter. We crossed the famous Pont Neuf, and had ice cream at a shop behind Paris St. Germaine. We then walked to Latin quarter for some Lunch. I had Fellafel wrap and my wife had some chicken wrap thing with fries.</p>

<p>We then walked towards the Notre Dame, which was still closed for renovations, and got into the famous Shakespeare and Co. book shop. I bought Around the world in 80 days in French (5 Euro), along with Flowers of Evil by Charles Baudelaire in French+English (14 Euro). My wife bought a Shakespeare and Co. totebag (18 Euro).</p>

<p>We then walked through a quaint street called the Rue de Mouffetard, then onto Luxembourg garden where we sat with a Bagel and wine in good weather for almost 2 hours. We then walked to our hotel just 1 km away. Another day of 20000+ steps!</p>

<h1 id="day-2---sunday-19th-may-2024">Day 2 - Sunday, 19th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="catacombs-montparnasse-semetary-sacre-couer-and-montmarte">Catacombs, Montparnasse Semetary, Sacre Couer and Montmarte</h2>

<p>We had prebooked tickets to the Catacombs for 10:45, Sunday, 19th May. A 20 minute walk to Denfert got us near the entry point. Going doen 20m by steps the Catacombs are a macabre experience but gives good insight into the Parisien history.
Exit through the goft shop, we were not very far from the entry itself. We walked to Montparnasse Cemetary. Here I visited the graves of Charles Baudelaire (where a bird pooped on me!), Emile Durkheim and Jean Paul Sartre. Walking towards Gare Montparnasse we saw an art market as well.</p>

<p>Taking a rest at the hotel, and me, a bath!, we left for Sacre Couer / Montmarte by metro, getting off at Abssess. Montmarte was a beautiful as we had read about it, and crowded as well. We took the Furnicular just for the heck of it (Metro tickets are valid here). Walking down we even saw Moulin Rouge and the equivalent of red ligh tarea of Paris. Not so seedy in day time.</p>

<p>We too ka metro back to Montparnasse to end our another day of 20k+ steps.</p>

<h1 id="day-3---monday-20th-may-2024">Day 3 - Monday, 20th May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="arc-de-triomphe-trecadero-pont-de-lena">Arc de Triomphe, Trecadero, Pont de Lena.</h2>

<p>Not as eventful as the other days, we started with the Arc De Triomphe and the shopping area of Champs de Elysee. I bought 23 Euro Adidas shorts at Decathelon. Zara, Uniclo etc. have the same clothes as the Indian chains and same price and quality too.</p>

<p>We walked to Tracedero, taking lot of photos of Eiffel from here. We walked to Pont Neuf as weather had begun to detoriate. It started raining by the time we reached Pont Neuf. We had to take shelter under the bridge for almost 1 hour. We then took same bus #800 to Montparnasse.
We decided to go on dinner date, again in Montparnasse. Today there was a signging concert going on where the art market had been the day before. We sat nearby at Restaurant Pinoccio, ordered wine and sphagetti pasta. The waitress even helped take our photographs.</p>

<h1 id="day-4---tuesday-21st-may-2024">Day 4 - Tuesday, 21st May 2024.</h1>
<h2 id="luxembourg-garden-gare-de-est">Luxembourg Garden, Gare de ‘Est</h2>

<p>Early morning i went running almost 10km. Going around Eiffel, Musee de Orsay, Luxembourg Garden and Montparnasse cemetary.
After checking out around 10:00 we walked to Luxembourg Gardens to read, eat breakfast and relax. At 12:00 we came back to Montparnasse to buy some souveniers and collect our baggage from the hotel. We then went to Gare De’ Est to catch our 15:55 TGV to Stuttgart.</p>

<p>We arrived in Stuttgart at almost 19:00 where we were received by my wife’s friend with flowers, cake and chocolates for our 1st anniversary!
We reached our hotel (Ibis Budget) by metro (U-bahn). We then went to dinner at a good Italian restaurant nearby (ARIA, Restaurante Enoteca).
The Porche Design Centre was just 100m from our hotel! There were even some vine gardens.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[For our first wedding anniversary we were determined to visit Paris, among other destinations in me and my wife’s first visit to Europe.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EuroTrip 2024 - The preperation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/05/Eurotrip-prep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EuroTrip 2024 - The preperation" /><published>2024-05-05T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/05/Eurotrip-prep</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/europe/2024/05/05/Eurotrip-prep.html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-itinerary">The Itinerary</h1>

<p>We started planning for our Euro trip in about mid Feb of 2024. “Euro trip” is somewhat of a umbrella term of wide range of experiences that the European continent has to offer. Mediterranean Italy, Greece and Spain have a different vibe compared to Traditional feel of France, Germany, Switzerland and much of Western Europe.
For me and my wife’s first “Euro Trip”, Paris we decided should be our first and most important stop. This was also influenced by the fact that most direct flights from India offer competitive prices to Paris.
Paris, great! what next? Hmm … Italy? Nice, lots of places to cover so for main destination as per Schengen Visa would be Italy. We could throw in Switzerland in the iternerary too. But upon checking VFS appointment dates for Italy, we saw that earliest available was 27th April. We intented to be on our tour for our wedding anniversary (May 21st) so 3 weeks before our date of departure was somewhat of a risky call since Schengen visa is often delayed in summer. Italy being a popular summer destination.
So, we checked VFS appointments for Germany. 17th April. That seemed doable as we intented to depart on 17th May. Oficcially they say to apply no less than 2 weeks before date of departure, so 4 weeks seemed enough. We were always paranoid nevertheless.
We formed an itinerary around the big cities around Paris: Paris, Munich, Berlin and Amsterdam. We also included Stuttgart to visit a very close of my wife.
Our first step of the preperation was the following itinerary:
<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Paris-Stuttgart-Munich-Berlin-Amsterdam</code>
Having finalized city/date of entry and exit, we targetted getting the VFS Appointment for Germany on 17th April. Reserving the appoitment needed only Passport number and nothing else (Cost around Rs.2300 per person including SMS, courier fee etc.). We also wanted to buy the flight tickets before they got more expensive. During the one week we spent deciding on itinerary prices almost increased by 5k per ticket.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 5000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-flights">The Flights</h1>

<p>We wanted direct flights to avoid the trouble of layovers in weird places and the anxiety of misplaced luggage. Also given that our place of arrival (Paris) and departure (Amsterdam) were on popular routes a direct flight would not have been a problem. We booked AF-217, direct flight from Bombay (BOM T2) to Paris (CDG 2E) departing on 01:30 at night (morning) of 17th May. It cost approx Rs. 75,000, on official AF website. Offer like zero-cancellation charges was not applicable. We did not add checkin luggage which was another 5k per ticket. We added 1 baggage later a few days before departure, bringing our total cost to approx Rs.80,000 for 2 people. This was deducted in Euros since we payed to Air France and hence we got charged 4.13% Markup+GST on our credit card, so make sure you sort out forex before paying in foreighn currency!
Similarly the return flight was Air India AI-156 from Amsterdam Schiphol Airport (AMS) to Delhi IGI (DEL T3) with 6-7 hr layover the flight to Mumbai (BOM). Which cost approx 60,000 total for 2 people. Booked on Cleartrip. No offers. Payment made in INR so no markup charges.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 1,45,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-visa">The Visa</h1>

<p>One requires the Schengen Visa (C type) to visit Schengen Zone countries.
As mentioned before, even before booking flights we booked our appointment at VFS for Germany. For India this should be your first step as soon as you know the country you will be applying the Visa from (either longest duration os stay, or if there is a tie then country of entry). Our city fortunately had a VFS center processing Schengen Visas for Germany.
This cost about Rs 2300 per person including miscellaneous fees. Non refundable.</p>

<h1 id="accomodation">Accomodation</h1>

<p>While we waited for our appointment date to drag closer. 2 months from the day we booked the appoitment seemed like a long time. But we got busy ironing out our itinerary, like adding day trips to Neuschwanstein Castle and Innsbruck etc. Also accomodations were also getting more expensive so we got to that as well. Booking.com was our go to website for all our bookings. With long nights of comparing and researching neighbourhoods, we had acco booked for each night of our visit (no night travels were planned as all places in our itinerary were close by to each other).
We are not very familiar with AirBnB plus it wasnt allowing free cancellation, which was very important for us incase of emergency or our visa application fell through.
Paris was the most expensive, followed by Amsterdam. Munich too somewhat. Hostel experience is not bad in Europe plus we would be out and about almost entire daytime only coming back at night to rest, so we booked hostel beds in Munich and Amsterdam. Rest were hotel rooms are reasonable rates. All of them were were very close to the metro transit of their city.
Approx cost of 17 nights of hotels and hostel for two people: INR 1,70,000.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Hotel Terminus Montparnasse (4 nights) = EUR 531 (rebooked just 3 days before arrival as original booking was EUR 780+ !)</li>
  <li>Ibis Budget Hotel, Stuttgart (2 nights) = EUR 144</li>
  <li>10-bed mixed dorm, Euro Youth Hostel, Munich (4 nights) = EUR 400 (after 10% cash discount for accepting double bed in the dorm)</li>
  <li>The Social Hub Hotel, Alexanderplatz, Berlin (3 nights) = EUR 386</li>
  <li>4-bed mixed dorm, Meininger Hostel, Amstel, Amsterdam (3 nights) = EUR 443</li>
</ul>

<p>So total acco cost came to around INR 1,73,000 (approx 10k per night) for two people.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 3,25,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-event-tickets">The Event Tickets</h1>

<p>Summer in Europe is the mina tourist season and tickets to venues and events have to be boughts months or weeks in advance.
We booked tickets to the <em>Louvre Museum</em>, <em>Catacombs</em> in Paris and Tour of <em>Neuschwanstein Castle</em>.
Later when our Visa arrived, we also booked all train tickets (all on <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DB Navigator</code>) as well as a cruise on the river Seine.
May is not exactly summer so we found ourselves at many places able to get tickets by standing in queue for just 10-15 mins (Eiffel Tower, Nordkette (Top of Innsbruck), etc.).</p>
<ul>
  <li>Seine River Cruise (Bateaux Parisiens) = EUR 32</li>
  <li>Amsterdam Canal Cruise (Blue Boat) = EUR 50</li>
  <li>Louvre Museum = EUR 45</li>
  <li>Nordkette = EUR 91</li>
  <li>Neuschwanstein = EUR 40</li>
  <li>Catacombs = EUR 58</li>
  <li>Eiffel Tower = EUR 22</li>
</ul>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 3,56,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-documentation">The documentation</h1>

<p>This is somewhat of a headache for any Euro trip from India. The paperwork!
Primary paperwork is</p>
<ul>
  <li>The flight tickets to and from schengen zone</li>
  <li>Proof of accomodation</li>
  <li>Bank statements (3m)</li>
  <li>Payroll statements (3m)</li>
  <li>ITRV (2 FY)</li>
  <li>Cover letter</li>
  <li>Detailed Itinerary (with planned or confirmed modes of transport)</li>
  <li>Health Insurance</li>
  <li>Proof of Leave taken from employer</li>
  <li>Employment proof</li>
</ul>

<p>Few extra docs we did slip in were</p>
<ul>
  <li>Marriage certificate</li>
  <li>Tickets to events</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="appointment">Appointment</h1>

<p>Comes 17th April and things were pretty relaxed. We reached 10 mins early to the VFS Center. We got in the 8:30am queue when it was time. Inside they screened through all docs and were given a token and directed to relevant kiosk where when our term came we submitted them  where our biometric was taken and we also paid for the visa (EUR 80 per person).
Not many comments here .. its better to take a appointment early in the day .. ours was 8:30am and there were still quite a lot of people there.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 3,71,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="cash-in-euro">Cash in Euro</h1>

<p>The prmary motivation to get a forex card was 4.13% Markup+GST cost for using our credit card to pay in euros.
I got ICICI Sappiro Travel Card cost about 3k (or 3.5k with tax). It came with a backup card incase the primary one got compromised. Also INR 1000 Uber voucher and international lounge massaage voulcher.
I switched all my accomodation payments on booking.com as soon as i got my forex card delivered (in 1 week after applying).
For cash I used BookMyForex as recommended by a friend. It assigned a company called Zenith something in my city which delivered it within 5 days (included a weekend). I ordered Euro 450. They gave 4 notes of 100 and one of 50. Smaller change would have been nicer but no problem.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 4,35,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-mobile-plans">The Mobile plans</h1>

<p>Me and wife both have Airtel service prepaid SIM cards, so we got 10 day and 30 day international plan which included 1 and 5 GB data and cost approx Rs.900 and Rs.3000.
Local sims in Europe cost around 30-50 Euros but could come with attractive data offers. Data is expensive in Europe.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 4,39,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="the-train-tickets">The Train Tickets</h1>

<p>We used DB (Deutsch Bahn) Navigator for all our trains.
A TGV for Paris to Stuttgart, then IC/ICE for Stuttgart-Munich, RER for Munich-Fussen-Munich (This trip we did under Bayern ticket which is just 39 Euro per day for a group of 5 people), IC/ICE for Munich to Berlin and Berlin to Amsterdam.
Costs were fairly reasonable, much less than flights and very convinient for us. Very comfortable too.
Approx Cost INR 60,000 (not sure!)</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 5,00,000</em></strong></p>

<h1 id="conclusion-on-cost-estimate">Conclusion on cost estimate</h1>

<p>The above cost trackers estimates the approx cost for almost all aspects of the tour except food and souveniers, which largely depends on personal preferrences. Our food costs were approx EUR 40-45 per day for both of use combined. At times a nice sitdown meal was alone EUR 40-50 but for most of the meals were under EUR 20.
Since I paid everything out of my Forex card (except the flights) its easy to estimate the tour cost on Food and Miscallaneous. For me that comes to around INR 90,000, which includes the events cost so lets add 60k to end the tracker.
FYI, I had put EUR 3200 on my card before departing. 5 days into the trip i put additional EUR 1600 just to be safe since I would be paying almost EUR 2k just for acco and i needed doh for grub etc. After arriving back in india I had approx EUR 1100 on my card. This was primarily due to this weird policy of “Card Pre-Authorization” done by hotels. The Paris hotel did this equivalent to cost of first day at the hotel. This amount is refunded after your stay by the hotel cancelling the preauthorization. Now not sure how this works in other banks, but in ICICI you get this amount back in your account after 30 days! So, I got my preauthorization charges back in my account AFTER I returned to India. BTW this preauthorization charge was deducted almost 7-10 days before day of arrival, keep that in mind. No other Hotel did this though.</p>

<p><strong><em>COST TRACKER: INR 5,60,000</em></strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="europe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Itinerary]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vacation to Meghalaya and Kaziranga</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2024/01/02/NorthEast.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vacation to Meghalaya and Kaziranga" /><published>2024-01-02T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2024-01-02T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2024/01/02/NorthEast</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2024/01/02/NorthEast.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 1</em> : Travel to SHILLONG</p>

<ul>
  <li>Arrive by direct flight to Guwahati at 0540Hrs</li>
  <li>Direct taxi to shillong
    <ul>
      <li>Swift Desire</li>
      <li>Courteous Bengali driver</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Breakfast at Jiva Veg (Nongpoh)
    <ul>
      <li>Super clean toilet.</li>
      <li>Awesome Poori Bhaji!</li>
      <li>Grilled sandwich gets fries on the side :-)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Stop at Umium Lake
    <ul>
      <li>Boating point opens at 0900Hrs</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Visited Ward’s Lake</li>
  <li>Visited Don Bosco Museum (taking in camera costs extra)</li>
  <li>Cafe Shillong for dinner</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 2</em> : CHERRAPUNJEE</p>

<ul>
  <li>Morning ride to Double Decker Root Bridge trek
    <ul>
      <li>Steps will give muscle pain for two days!</li>
      <li>also visited single root bridge enroute</li>
      <li>feet nibbling fish at pool under the bridge (ticklish!)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Night at Jiva Resort in Cherapunjee (Sohra)
    <ul>
      <li>Bonfire with other residents</li>
      <li>Awesome view from room (sun rise)</li>
      <li>Nice landscaping</li>
      <li>Complementary golf shots (20 per room)</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 3</em> : SHILLONG</p>

<ul>
  <li>Nohkalikai Waterfall
    <ul>
      <li>Dont miss the trail in the grassland beyond the view point</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Dawki boating
    <ul>
      <li>cross the bridge to bangla/south side (avoid touts on Meghalaya/North side)</li>
      <li>INR 800 ticket per boat</li>
      <li>Bangladesh border is just stones near the river!</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Mawlynnong Village</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 4</em> : SHILLONG</p>

<ul>
  <li>Police Bazar
    <ul>
      <li>Christmas decorations!</li>
      <li>insane crowd</li>
      <li>Dinner at chinese restaurant</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Shyllong Peak</li>
  <li>Elephant Falls
    <ul>
      <li>Three tier waterfall</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>ML 05 cafe
    <ul>
      <li>Cool ambience, biking theme</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 5</em> : SHILLONG</p>

<ul>
  <li>Bamboo Trek (Mawryngkhang)
    <ul>
      <li>Swimming at natural pool of Mawreh river!</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Deja Vu restaurant</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 6</em> : GUWAHATI</p>

<ul>
  <li>Bhramaputra River Heritage Centre</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 7</em> : Siju (South Garo Hills, Meghalaya)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Gowshala (Maligaon)</li>
  <li>Sameng River</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 8</em> : Siju (South Garo Hills, Meghalaya)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Wari Chora</li>
  <li>Jadesil Fish Sanctuary</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 9</em> : Guwahati</p>

<ul>
  <li>Siju Caves</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 10</em> : Borgos Resort (Kaziranga)</p>

<ul>
  <li>Borgos Resort</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 11</em> : Guwahati</p>

<ul>
  <li>Lush Cafe and Qalaa Bakery (Silpukhri)</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 12</em> : Return to Pune</p>

<ul>
  <li>Kamakhaya Temple</li>
  <li>Maligaon</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="india" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 1 : Travel to SHILLONG]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Vacation in Kerala</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2023/09/20/Kerala.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vacation in Kerala" /><published>2023-09-20T00:06:16+05:30</published><updated>2023-09-20T00:06:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2023/09/20/Kerala</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/india/2023/09/20/Kerala.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Day 1</em> : Kochi</p>

<ul>
  <li>Bolgatty Palace Resort</li>
  <li>Jew Town</li>
  <li>Chinese Fishing Nets</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 2</em> : Alleppey</p>

<ul>
  <li>Leleela Resort</li>
  <li>Beach</li>
  <li>Kayaking</li>
  <li>Swimming</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 3</em> : Alleppey</p>

<ul>
  <li>Boating</li>
  <li>Ayurved massage</li>
  <li>Beach</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 4</em> : Munnar</p>

<ul>
  <li>The Fog Resort</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 5</em> : Munnar</p>

<ul>
  <li>Station Top</li>
  <li>Echo point</li>
  <li>Boating</li>
  <li>Botanical Garden</li>
  <li>Tea Gardens view point</li>
</ul>

<p><em>Day 6</em> : Pune</p>

<ul>
  <li>National Park</li>
  <li>Tea Museum</li>
  <li>Return to Kochi</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="travel" /><category term="india" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Day 1 : Kochi]]></summary></entry></feed>